Ray Garner

ray@perfectcast.co.uk raygarner.co.uk

Personal Profile

I chose to study Computer Science because I find the work of software engineers like John Carmack and Linus Torvalds highly inspiring and also because I find programming exercises my imagination in a unique way. Developing software gives me a similar sense of satisfaction as composing music does, a prolific hobby of mine. Along with composing music, I have enjoyed playing in a variety of musical ensembles for several years now. This experience gave me the opportunity to practice my teamwork skills and creativity to a great extent, which quickly became useful during the group work project in the first year of my degree studies.

Education and Qualifications

University of Nottingham

- 2020-Present Studying in 2nd year of Computer Science Bsc. Core modules include software engineering group project, operating systems & concurrency, algorithms & efficiency and I've opted for optional modules in advanced functional programming, C++ programming and AI methods.
- 2019-2020 Attained a 1st with 87% overall in year 1 of Computer Science Bsc. Core modules included programming & algorithms, maths for computer science, systems & architecture, databases & interfaces and fundamentals of AI.

Wigston Academy Trust

- 2017-2019 Achieved A, A, B in A-Level Computer Science, Music Technology and Music
- 2015-2017 Passed 11 GCSEs with grades A*-B

RSL

• 2018 - Passed Grade 8 electric guitar with merit

Software Tools Experience

Software development	vim, gcc, gdb, ghc, vscode, Eclipse IDE, JUnit testing, MATLAB, Visual Studio, Chrome dev tools, git, make
Multimedia	Reaper, Cubase, Ardour, ffmpeg, Audacity, Avid Sibelius, Musescore, GIMP, Blender
Network tools	ftp, ssh, Citrix Receiver, VMware Horizon, TeamViewer
Design	Google SketchUp, Circuit Wizard
Languages	C, ARM asm, Java, Haskell, MySQL, JavaScript, PHP, VB.NET, shell script, HTML, CSS, IATEX, Markdown
Operating systems	Arch Linux, Debian Linux, Windows 7 onwards, macOS Sierra onwards

Software Development Projects

- 2019-Present Maintain shell scripts to automate the installation and configuration of Arch Linux to my preferences
- 2020 Created a shell script wrapper for mpv and ffmpeg to create a multi-track recording tool
- 2020 Programmed a chess engine in Haskell using an alpha-beta search with a university colleague and later developed a faster version of the program in C
- 2020 Set up a film database website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL for the coursework in the databases and interfaces module in year one of my degree. I now maintain raygarner.co.uk as a portfolio using skills I learned during that project
- 2020 Wrote JUnit tests to debug a faulty finance app in the first group work module of my degree and also used git for version control

- 2020 Utilised the Java GUI library "swing" and object oriented programming techniques to create a Minesweeper game as a university assignment
- 2019 Completed various assignment exercises to gain experience with C, ARM asm, Java and Haskell during the first year of my degree
- 2018-2019 Created a primitive chess engine using VB.NET for A-Level Computer Science coursework for the college chess club

Work Experience

2017-2020 - Perfectcast Ltd

- Upgraded laptop hardware
- Performed corporate laptop imaging
- Installed a Cisco video conference system
- Set up a Blender renderfarm
- Carried out end-user and network IT support

2016-2019 - Wigston Academy Trust

- Played as the guitarist for the shows Joseph and his amazing Technicolour Dreamcoat, Little Shop of Horrors, Annie and School of Rock
- Recording technician for GCSE Music recitals

2019 - The Little Theatre

• Played as the guitarist for their production of Cats

Hobbies and Other Experience

Music

- 2020 Played as lead guitarist and co-producer in Leicester math-rock band "PE Department"
- 2019-2020 Performed as lead guitarist in the Wigston College Jazz Band
- 2015-2019 Performed as lead guitarist in Leicester alt-rock band "The Scrubs"
- 2014 Sung in the choir in "The Armed man: A mass for Peace" at the Royal Albert Hall
- 2014 Played guitar in Rhys Chatham's "A Secret Rose" Birmingham Town Hall performance

Chess

- 2020-Present Member of the University of Nottingham Chess Society
- 2019-2020 Head of the Wigston College Chess Club

References available upon request